For some time now, I've been receiving calls from many customers
who want to invest in a Uli policy
and want to know
about investing in a good Uli policy. So,
I'm going to make some videos
on Uli. Today,
I'm presenting to you the first video, Bajaj
Life Insurance's Future Wealth Gain to
Plan. This is an excellent product
because the customer's
first requirement is that they want
a plan with good returns in equity. The second
requirement is that they get tax
benefits. Here, you'll get a tax benefit on an ATC of ₹1 lakh. The
third
requirement is that whatever returns
they receive are tax-free. So,
here you'll get tax-free returns
if you invest up to ₹1 lakh. The
customer's requirement is that
they also get insurance cover, which would be
great. So, here you
can get insurance cover up to 40 times the premium. Suppose
you pay a premium of ₹1 lakh and get an
insurance cover of ₹1 crore.  You can
also avail the benefits of riders and
along with this Bajaj Ace Life Insurance has
also launched a new fund for ULIP on 1 July 2024.
I am giving information about that fund
in this video as well. You
can invest in that too and earn good returns. Here, excellent combined features of tax benefit,
returns and insurance have been
given and
you will get all the features in a single plan. So
come, let us understand the plan in details in this video
and if you like the video, then if
my
YouTube channel is 4 thousand or more then here
you will have to pay zero premium allocation charges.
Normally,
premium allocation charges of around 12 rupees are levied. Here
also, suppose you purchase a policy of 500 rupees or
12000 rupees, then premium allocation charges will be levied.
45000 rupees will be spent on your charges.
If it is a policy of 1 lakh rupees, then around
0000 rupees are levied as premium allocation charges.
But in this policy, investment up to ₹ 1 lakh is possible.
On doing this, your maturity
comes tax free, you
get a tax benefit of ₹1 lakh plus premium
allocation charges will be zero. In 20224, Bajaj
Ellis Life Insurance has launched a new fund
named Nifty Alpha 50
Index Fund. It is open till 15th July 2024
and you will get it with an initial investment of around ₹10.
As Business
Standard has shared this news
with you, here for those who
want to get high returns, your investment will be in high alpha stocks here.
You can invest till 15th July. Here,
this company will have 300 top stocks in the last 6 months,
according to their market capitalization, your investment will be in the top 50 funds.
If you notice here,
in the last 10 years, this benchmark has
given a return of 26% and in the last 5 years,
its return is 32.9%.
If you look at the news of this benchmark, Mint
newspaper has also covered it.  That Bajaj
Allianz has launched a new fund in the Uli policy
and all the other
news outlets like Financial Express etc. have
also covered this new fund, so
you can invest here and earn a good
return. Here you will
invest in Top Alpha Fund and
here you can earn a good return by
investing in the new fund.
In this plan, you are given two options - Wealth
Plus and Wealth Plus Care, which I am going to cover in this video.
Talking about all the benefits and features of Wealth Plus, the ability
criteria, in Wealth Plus, a
child of zero years i.e. a
person from 60 years can purchase the policy
and if you take more than one rider,
then the maximum age will be 50 years, maximum
maturity will be 75 years, minimum maturity will be 18 years. The
premium payment term here will be from five
years to 10 years if
you take the policy term for 10 years. If you
take a policy for 15 years to 25 years, then the
premium payment  You can take any one of 5 years, 7 years, 10 years or 15
years. If we
talk about the minimum premium, then
you can purchase this policy for ₹5000000 annual premium
and if we talk about sum assured, the most
important thing is sum assured, that too
in ULIP. If you notice that
between your age of zero to 25 years, then you can
take insurance up to 40 times the annual premium
.  If you pay a premium of Rs 1 lakh, you will get
insurance up to Rs 1 crore. If
you are between 26 to 35 years of age, then you will get
insurance of 30 times the annual premium, that is, you will get insurance of Rs 75 lakh. If you are
above Rs 1 lakh and are between 36 to
40 years of age, then you can take 20 times insurance cover. If you are
between 41 to 44 years of
age,
you will get 15 times insurance. If you are 45 and above, then you will get 10
times insurance cover. As long as you get 10 times insurance cover, its
upcoming maturity is tax free.
If the insurance is less than 10 times, then the
maturity is taxable. And
if you invest up to Rs 1 lakh, then the
maturity is tax free.
If you invest above Rs 1 lakh, then the maturity
is taxable. If you continue with the
policy and remain loyal
with Bajaj Ella, then you
also get loyalty benefit, which is
a certain percentage of your annual premium, it will be
added to your fund value.
After a gap of 5 years, the royalty addition that you will get for the first time will be given in the
10th year of the policy.
Suppose you are paying a premium of ₹1 lakh, then
₹1 will be added to your fund value. In the
15th year, you will get 25%, in the 20th year, 25% and
finally in the 25th year, 30%
of annual premium will be
added to your fund value in the
name of loyalty addition. Along with the loyalty addition,
you will also be given the benefit of a fund booster.
You will get the fund booster
at maturity, that is, in the
last year of the policy. It will be
a certain portion of your annual premium. Suppose your
policy term is 15 years or more
and the premium payment term was
kept for 10 years, then you will get 60% of your annual premium as
fund booster.
For different PPTs, you
can see the picture on the side here.
You will get another extra benefit.  Which will last for the
last 3 years, at that time,
not the annual premium of the fund value, but up to
1% or half of the average of the last 3 years of the fund value will be given in the
name of family
benefit. By the name of family benefit, it means if
any policy of yours, your spouse's parents' grand parents' parents-in-law's sister's brother's child is
running in Bajaj Life Insurance and you are purchasing this policy through
Wealth Connect and if your
policy term is less than 20 years, then
half percent of your fund value and if the policy term is 20 years or
more, then 1% of your fund
value. Suppose the fund value is one crore, then
you will get one lakh rupees as a family benefit.
Now let us see the fund performance of
different funds in ULIP of Bajaj Allians Life Insurance.
Ever since this product was launched,
like equity funds, you have been given many
equity funds for investment here, there are
hybrid funds, debt funds,
liquid funds, in this way many
funds have been given to you. Now if you
notice here, here  Absolute returns are
also given. Plus, here you are
also given the details of compound interest CAGR.
Details of every fund are given here, whether it is a deep-side fund, a
cash-side fund, a large-cap fund, or a
small-cap fund. All these details are
given here. Returns for one year, two years, three
years, five years, and ten years are also given here.
Returns from the inception date of the fund have also been mentioned since the fund was launched.
For example, if you look at the returns of your large cap,
from 2004 onwards, the
returns are given at 15, 16, 1658 in this manner.
If we talk about small cap, the
fund which was launched in 2023 in the month of May as a
small cap fund, its one-year return is
6869.
You can also see the returns of other funds here. You can also see the returns
of multi-cap funds.
Returns are given in this manner at 15, 16, 1658
and here you  I will try to explain to you a little about
how the investment is made and which
funds are invested in. Let's
assume that you take a fund called
Equity Mid Cap Plus Fund. This fund was launched on
March 9, 2005. At that time,
its face value was 0 and its risk profile is
very high because it is an equity fund.
Its benchmark is Nifty Mid Cap 50
Index. The fund manager is
Anshul Mishra who manages your fund.
And here you will see
that the NV of 10 has increased to 216. On May 31,
2024, you have an
AY of Rs 158 crore under this policy
and in equity,
you are investing around Rs 50 crore.
Here, on the left
side, see what percentage is going into equity. It is
94, out of which how much is going
into large cap and how much is going into mid cap stocks.
And how much is being invested in debt funds.
You
can see this here. In which companies are invested here.
Investments are made, for example, Bharat
Electronics is investing 3.16%,
Power Finance is investing
2.76%, TVS Motors is
also investing 2.63%, Shriram Finance is investing
2.47%. Investments in different companies are
also mentioned here.
Here, you can see the risk profile, including the
equity portion invested,
and the remaining investment.
In the top 10 sectors, the financial and insurance sector is investing
17.77%, and
manufacturing is
investing 10.6%. In this way,
you can see how your investment will go in different sectors.
If you look at the returns of this fund,
you have been earning 1.32% since inception, and
17.3% since 2005.
In this policy,
you can invest in different funds according to your risk profile
and earn a good
return.  Now let's understand the
future wealth gain to benefit illustration of Bajaj Allianz Life Insurance. Let's
assume that there is a
35-year-old man named
Anil Rajput, whose channel name is Anil
Rajput LFS. He purchases a policy
from Bajaj where he invests Rs 2.5 lakh.
Because on
investing up to Rs 1 lakh, the return on maturity in ULIP is
tax-free. Here you will see
that the customer's
policy term is 25 years. He is taking a 25-year policy.
He is choosing a premium payment term of 10 years.
He is paying a premium of Rs 1 lakh.
And look at the insurance cover, it is Rs 1 crore, that is,
40 times the premium.
Whereas in ULIPs,
most of the ULIPs have 10 times the
insurance of Rs 25 lakh. But here, the
insurance cover is Rs 1 crore.
You can see the name of the product here. Unit
Insurance Policy is mentioned here.
And here I have shown many different
funds just to show you.  There are so many
funds available and you
can invest what percentage in a particular fund or in many funds.
You can invest in so many funds keeping in mind whether your
risk profile is high, very high, moderate or
low. You can invest in so
many funds accordingly.
Now, I have kept an
insurance cover of Rs 1 crore in the base plan.
Along with this, I have
also kept an accidental death benefit cover of Rs 1 crore and
disability cover of Rs 1 crore.
This will be a 25-year policy term. The
premium has to be paid only for 10 years.
Your premium up to Rs 1 lakh is Rs 1 lakh or the rider
premium which comes to Rs
107.25. And here you notice that the total amount you have to
pay is Rs 2629 because your base
premium is Rs 1 lakh, hence the maturity will be tax
free. Riders are separate. Now you will
notice here that the best thing
I am telling you is that
even on a premium of Rs 1 lakh, the commission to the agent is only Rs
100, whereas  In 20078, the
commission used to be 40-50%, so
in comparison to other mutual funds, this mutual fund has
also become better than other mutual funds because if you
invest Rs 1 lakh in mutual fund and if you die tomorrow,
what will you get? Rs 1 lakh, Rs 3 lakh,
but here you will get Rs 1 crore and the
chances of death of a 25-year-old man
in an accident are higher, so there is
also an accidental rider, so you will get Rs 2 crore. The
second good thing is that let me
tell you one more thing here, the premium allocation
charges are zero, whereas
in other ULIPs, there are premium allocation charges up to 12%, so if there were
allocation charges of 12% above Rs 2 lakh, then Rs
30,000 of yours would have gone in charges, so
here there are no charges, there are
zero allocation charges, so the money is getting
invested, plus you are
getting loyalty addition as well, here you get Rs 15 in the
10th year, Rs 20 in the 15th year,
then in this way you  You
got a royalty addition of Rs 62500. This is the annual premium of the premium.
This is at 15%, this is at 20%,
this is at 25%. Plus, you
also get a booster benefit at the end of the policy,
which will be around 60% of your annual premium. So,
after adding all this, it gets
added to the fund value as well. So,
you paid Rs 2 lakh in 10 years. In 25 years,
you got around Rs 88 lakh, 8738, 888 lakh, 89 lakh at
maturity, that too tax free, that too
only at 8%, as shown in the table here.
Whereas, if you look at the actual returns
in the fund performance, from the time of inception till
2004, then the return is of Rs 15, 16,
17, 18% and the one-year
return is up to Rs 68, 69%. So, here you will
definitely get returns more than this and
you also have insurance cover and tax-free
benefit. If you withdraw money after 5 years,  If you
want,
you will also get the facility of partial withdrawal. Now let me tell you one more option,
suppose the maturity amount of Rs. 88 lakhs is being
made here, the insurance cover is Rs. 1
crore. Now suppose I had taken
10 times insurance instead of 40 times in this product, then
my insurance cover would have been Rs. 25 lakhs only.
Well, here also I am
getting accidental cover etc. of Rs. 25 lakhs. My
premium is Rs. 2500000. There is a slight difference in the premium
but there is
no major difference in the maturity.
How much difference will you see in the maturity? If you have 93 lakhs, then
you are seeing 5 lakhs more in maturity
but the insurance cover is only Rs. 25 lakhs. So
if you want to take more insurance cover, then
also you have the option and if you are
looking towards maturity, then also you have the
option whether you should go with less insurance
or not.
I would say that when you are coming to an insurance company,
then first focus on the insurance, okay,
because in a 40 times UL plan,
hardly anyone will give you that insurance.  40 Times: There are
very few products where you
get insurance at 40 times the premium.
Talking about other benefits and
features in the equity plan, here you will
get the benefit of switching. If you want to switch from one fund to another,
you can do so.
You will
also get the option to reduce the premium. For example, if
you want to reduce the premium you were paying by 50% after 5 years, you
can do so. Suppose you were
paying a premium of ₹1 lakh, after 5 years you
felt that you cannot afford the premium of ₹1 lakh. If you
want to reduce it,
you can continue the policy by paying a premium of up to ₹1.25 lakh.
Option to change
premium payment time: If you
want to reduce or increase the premium payment time after 5 years, you can do so. If you
also want to change the frequency of premium payment, you can do so.
Suppose you want to switch
from annual mode to monthly mode,
from monthly mode to annual mode or quarterly
or semi-annual mode.  If you want to go in annual mode, you
can go. The policy also has a top-up facility
and partial withdrawal
benefit. After five years, if you
want to withdraw money from the policy,
you can do partial withdrawal, but the
fund value should be equal to minimum three annual premiums. You will
get tax benefit under Income Tax Section ATC up
to ₹ lakh and tax-free income under 101D.
If the investment is up to ₹ lakh,
this policy has a surrender
benefit. You can surrender the policy after 5 years. The
revival period will be 3 years.
If for some reason you are unable to pay the premium on time,
you can revive the policy by paying late fees etc. for 3 years. You
can restart the policy again. There will be a
grace period in this policy. There will also be a
free look period of 30 days. Now
IRDA has made it 30 days. Earlier it used to be 15 days.
You will also get a free look period of 30 days.
This policy does not offer a loan facility, as it is an equity-
based plan. Finally, if I were to summarize this plan, it
is a great plan
for those who want high returns, are
taking risks, but expect high returns.
Those who are
getting 40 times insurance cover, tax benefits, and
tax-free income are also available. For those who
look at ELSS in mutual funds,
where they can get tax benefits and
also invest, it
is even better because they are getting tax benefits,
tax-free income, and
insurance cover up to 40 times.
If this is more, then they are getting 30 times, 20 times more
insurance. Different
funds are available. New funds have also come, and
you can invest in new funds as well.
You can switch from one fund to another for free.
Mutual funds have
many things like entry load, exit load, etc.
So, here you will
get good returns, good funds are also available, and
new funds are also getting insurance
tax.  Benefits and many other things There are
no premium allocation charges if
you pay a premium of Rs 240000 or more There are
many
policies given to you for premium payment You
can take them as per your need You
can select the policy term Plus many
good riders are also given in it If you
want to take accidental rider then you can
take accidental rider If you
want to take disability rider then you
can also add disability rider So you
can make this policy more attractive with the rider
If you want to purchase this policy from me then
call
Please subscribe to my channel Anil Rajput Triple FS There you will
find more than 350 videos which will
help you in your financial planning Jai Hind